

POSTDOCTORAL RESEARCHER IN INTERACTIVE ROBOT LEARNING

COGNITIVE ROBOTICS, MECHANICAL ENGINEERING, TU DELFT, THE NETHERLANDS ·

About

I am seeking a Research Scientist position in Robot Learning starting from September 2024. I have over 6 years of experience in learning and performing complex real-world manipulation tasks and interactive learning from human teachers. I completed my doctoral studies developing control and learning strategies for safe and flexible robot learning, focusing on both single and bimanual manipulation. I have managed students and collaborated with PhD and Postdoctoral researchers on projects, including robot dressing, assembly tasks, surface cleaning/polishing, supermarket reshelving, and plant harvesting. I advocate open source, knowledge sharing, and teaching. I actively help colleagues in my university and the whole community advance in the complex field of robot learning. My controllers and algorithms are deployed in different labs for safer human-robot interaction and learning.

Skills

Robot Control Variable Impedance Control for Single and Bimanual Manipulation. Safe human-robot interaction.

Robot Learning Low-level and high-level skill learning from human interactive demonstrations.

Machine Learning Gaussian Process. Epistemic Uncertainty Estimation and Calibration. Variational Inference.

Project Management I have managed six Master projects independently and many others in collaboration with other researchers.

Programming Object-oriented programming (Python and C++). Robotic Operating System (ROS), Scientific Writing (LaTeX)

Languages English, Italian

Experience

PostDoc @ Delft University of Technology

Delft, Netherlands

POSTDOCTORAL RESEARCH. MENTOR: COSIMO DELLA SANTINA. NXTGEN HIGH-TECH AGRI-FOOD PROJECT.

Sep. 2023 - now

Managing the Franka Emika lab of Cognitive Robotics, TU Delft. Investigating learning-based methods for improving the reliability of low-cost, soft, and deformable hardware. Experimenting with generalizing manipulation skills in plant branch cutting.

Robothon Manipulation Challenge 2023

Delft, Netherlands

TEAM LEADER PLATONICS TEAM FOR ROBOTHON CHALLENGE 2023.

April. 2023 - May. 2023

Completed the task using a fully interactive learned-from-demonstrations approach combining proprioceptive and visual information.

Visiting Ph.D. @ UCL (University College London)

London, United Kingdom

VISITING Ph.D. IN STATISTICAL MACHINE LEARNING GROUP. MENTOR: MARC DEISENROTH.

Sep. 2022 - Feb 2023

I focused on variational inference learning methods to perform calibrated classification on high-dimensional inputs like images or graphs.

Education

Ph.D. @ Delft University of Technology

Delft, Netherlands

Ph.D. in Interactive Imitation Learning for Robotics in Department of Cognitive Robotics. ERC grant TERI

(TEACHING ROBOT INTERACTIVELY). THESIS: UNCERTAINTY-AWARE INTERACTIVE IMITATION LEARNING FOR ROBOT

June. 2019 - June 2023

Manipulation. Mentor: Jens Kober, Luka Peternel. Official defense: September 2024.

Visiting M.Sc. @ Eindhoven University of Technology

Eindhoven, Netherlands

ERASMUS+ MASTER THESIS IN DEPARTMENT OF DYNAMICS AND CONTROL. MENTOR: ALESSANDRO SACCON. THESIS: ON COMPUTING SECOND DERIVATIVES IN OPTIMAL MOTION PLANNING FOR ROBOT MANIPULATORS.

Feb. 2018 - July 2018

M.Sc. @ Politecnico di Milano

Milano, Italy

M.Sc. Masters Degree in Mechatronics and Robotics (107/110)

Sept. 2016 - Dec. 2018

B.Sc. @ Politecnico di Milano

Milano, Italy

BACHELOR DEGREE IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING (104/110)

Sept 2013 - Sept 2016

Teaching

2022,23,24 **Lecturer on Gaussian Process for Robotics and Control** MSc course Intelligent Control Systems

TU Delft

2020,21 **Teaching Assistant** MSc course Machine Learning for Robotics

TU Delft

Selected Publications _____

	Generalization of Task Parameterized Dynamical Systems using Gaussian Process	
024	Transportation Giovanni Franzese, Ravi Prakash, and Jens Kober, in Transaction of Robotics. (Under review)	T-RO
023	Do You Need a Hand?-a Bimanual Robotic Dressing Assistance Scheme Jihong Zhu, Michael	T-RO
023	Gienger, Giovanni Franzese, Jens Kober, in Transaction of Robotics.	
023	Interactive Imitation Learning of Bimanual Movement Primitives Giovanni Franzese, Leandro de	T-MECH
023	Souza Rosa, Tim Verburg, Luka Peternel, Jens Kober, in Transaction of Mechatronics	
	Interactive Imitation Learning in Robotcs: A Survey Carlos Celemin, Rodrigo Pérez-Dattari,	Foundations and
023	Eugenio Chisari, Giovanni Franzese, Leandro de Souza Rosa, Ravi Prakash, Zlatan Ajanović, Marta	Trends® in Robotics
	Ferraz, Abhinav Valada, Jens Kober. Foundations and Trends® in Robotics	Hends- III Robotics
022	Learning to Pick at Non-Zero-Velocity from Interactive Demonstrations A Mészáros, G Franzese,	RA-L
022	J Kober. Robotics and Automation Letter (RA-L)	
021	ILoSA: Interactive Learning of Stiffness and Attractors G Franzese, A Mészáros, L Peternel, J	IROS
021	Kober. International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems	
020	Learning interactively to resolve ambiguity in reference frame selection G Franzese, CE Celemin,	CoRL
020	J Kober. COnference of Robot Learning	

Awards_____

2022	TAILOR Connectivity found Awarded 15.000 € for visiting University College London from	
	September 2022 to February 2023	
2022	ELLIS PhD Student ELLIS PhDs conduct cutting-edge curiosity-driven research in machine learning	
	or a related research area with the goal of publishing in top-tier conferences in the field.	
2022	Winner Franka-Emika Manipulation Hackathon at the European Robotics Forum	Rotterdam
2021	Winner of BEST LATE BREAKING RESULTS POSTER AWARD IEEE/ASME International Conference on	
	Advanced Intelligent Mechatronics (AIM)	